[
    {
        "Question": "The number of bones present in an Adult human is",
        "A": 106,
        "B": 206,
        "C": 306,
        "D": 406,
        "Correct_Answer": 206
    },
    {
        "Question": "What are the types of joint in Human",
        "A": "Hinge joint",
        "B": "Ball and Socket Joint",
        "C": "Gliding joint",
        "D": "All the above",
        "Correct_Answer": "All the above"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following joins is immovable?",
        "A": "Shoulder and arm",
        "B": "Knee joint",
        "C": "Upper jaw and skull",
        "D": "Lower jaw and upper jaw",
        "Correct_Answer": "Lower jaw and upper jaw"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following protects our lungs:",
        "A": "Cranium",
        "B": "Rib cage",
        "C": "Pelvic bones",
        "D": "Backbone",
        "Correct_Answer": "Rib cage"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which types of skelton is found in human",
        "A": "Exoskelton",
        "B": "Endoskelton",
        "C": "Both of the above",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Endoskelton"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is other name of soft bone?",
        "A": "Bone",
        "B": "Cartilage",
        "C": "Both of them",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Cartilage"
    },
    {
        "Question": "The joint which helps in rotating a body in all directions",
        "A": "Fixed joint",
        "B": "Hinge joint",
        "C": "Pivot joint",
        "D": "Ball and socket joint",
        "Correct_Answer": "Ball and socket joint"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not source of water?",
        "A": "Lake",
        "B": "River",
        "C": "Sea",
        "D": "Sky",
        "Correct_Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the function of food?",
        "A": "Energy to do work",
        "B": "Maintain our body",
        "C": "Remain healthy",
        "D": "Wasting energy",
        "Correct_Answer": "Wasting energy"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which to following is not the ingredients of Idli",
        "A": "Pulse",
        "B": "Rice",
        "C": "Water",
        "D": "Turmeric",
        "Correct_Answer": "Turmeric"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which pulse is the ingredient of Idli",
        "A": "Moong",
        "B": "masoor",
        "C": "Urad",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Urad"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is obtained from animal",
        "A": "Pulse",
        "B": "Flour",
        "C": "Milk",
        "D": "Soyabean",
        "Correct_Answer": "Milk"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is spice",
        "A": "Pulse",
        "B": "Flour",
        "C": "Turmeric",
        "D": "Salt",
        "Correct_Answer": "Turmeric"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not root?",
        "A": "Carrot",
        "B": "Radish",
        "C": "Potato",
        "D": "Turnip",
        "Correct_Answer": "Potato"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not stem?",
        "A": "Sweet potato",
        "B": "Ginger",
        "C": "Garlic",
        "D": "Turmeric",
        "Correct_Answer": "Turmeric"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which plant leave is not eaten as food?",
        "A": "Cabbage",
        "B": "lettuce",
        "C": "Spinach",
        "D": "Neem",
        "Correct_Answer": "Neem"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Among the following whose fruit and flower both are eaten as food?",
        "A": "Banana",
        "B": "Orange",
        "C": "Onion",
        "D": "Cauliflower",
        "Correct_Answer": "Banana"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not fruit which is eaten as food?",
        "A": "Tomato",
        "B": "Lady finger",
        "C": "Cabbage",
        "D": "Chilli",
        "Correct_Answer": "Cabbage"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not used as sprouts?",
        "A": "Moong",
        "B": "Wheat",
        "C": "Gram",
        "D": "Soyabean",
        "Correct_Answer": "Soyabean"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not ominvores?",
        "A": "Bear",
        "B": "Crow",
        "C": "Dog",
        "D": "rabbit",
        "Correct_Answer": "Rabbit"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not consumers?",
        "A": "Tiger",
        "B": "Cow",
        "C": "Cotton",
        "D": "Snake",
        "Correct_Answer": "Cotton"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not producer?",
        "A": "Cow",
        "B": "Mango tree",
        "C": "Banyan tree",
        "D": "mulberry tree",
        "Correct_Answer": "Cow"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Green plant make their food with the help of following:",
        "A": "Sunlight",
        "B": "Carbon di oxide",
        "C": "Water",
        "D": "All of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "All of them"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which is not obtained from the animals",
        "A": "Maize",
        "B": "Mutton",
        "C": "Milk",
        "D": "Ghee",
        "Correct_Answer": "Maize"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which part of turnip is eaten as food",
        "A": "Root",
        "B": "Stem",
        "C": "Leaves",
        "D": "Flower",
        "Correct_Answer": "Root"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which main part of onion is eaten?",
        "A": "Root",
        "B": "Stem",
        "C": "Leaves",
        "D": "Fruit",
        "Correct_Answer": "Stem"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which part of Dandelion is eaten?",
        "A": "Root",
        "B": "Stem",
        "C": "Flower",
        "D": "leaves",
        "Correct_Answer": "Flower"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which part of lettuce is eaten?",
        "A": "Root",
        "B": "Stem",
        "C": "Leaves",
        "D": "Fruit",
        "Correct_Answer": "Leaves"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not obtained from milk?",
        "A": "Ghee",
        "B": "Butter",
        "C": "Soya",
        "D": "Paneer",
        "Correct_Answer": "Soya"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Grasshopper is ..............",
        "A": "Herbivores",
        "B": "Carnivores",
        "C": "Omnivores",
        "D": "Decomposer",
        "Correct_Answer": "Herbivores"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Animal that eat both animal and plants are called....",
        "A": "Herbivores",
        "B": "Carnivores",
        "C": "Omnivores",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Omnivores"
    },
    {
        "Question": "The flower of which of the following plants are not eaten",
        "A": "Banana",
        "B": "Rose",
        "C": "Pumpkin",
        "D": "Bougainvillea",
        "Correct_Answer": "Bougainvillea"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following take food in the form of liquid only?",
        "A": "Snake",
        "B": "dog",
        "C": "butterfly",
        "D": "Kingfisher",
        "Correct_Answer": "Butterfly"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following are the component of foods?",
        "A": "Carbohydrates",
        "B": "Protein",
        "C": "Fats",
        "D": "All of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "All of them"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Carbohydrates are mainly obtained from?",
        "A": "Plants",
        "B": "animals",
        "C": "Decomposers",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Plants"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is rich source of protein obtained from plant?",
        "A": "Mutton",
        "B": "Soyabean",
        "C": "Milk",
        "D": "Cheese",
        "Correct_Answer": "Soyabean"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Energy giving food is called",
        "A": "Carbohydrates",
        "B": "Protein",
        "C": "Vitamins",
        "D": "Minerals",
        "Correct_Answer": "Carbohydrates"
    },
    {
        "Question": "What is the function of protein",
        "A": "Give energy",
        "B": "Stores in body",
        "C": "Give strength",
        "D": "Protect us against diseases",
        "Correct_Answer": "Protect us against diseases"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Vitamin A is necessary for",
        "A": "Keeping gum healthy",
        "B": "Keeping bone healthy",
        "C": "Keeping good eyesight",
        "D": "Make haemoglobin",
        "Correct_Answer": "Keeping good eyesight"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which vitamin is necessary for the healthy gum",
        "A": "Vitamin A",
        "B": "Vitamin B",
        "C": "Vitamin C",
        "D": "Vitamin D",
        "Correct_Answer": "Vitamin C"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which Vitamin is necessary for the proper growth of bones and teeth?",
        "A": "Vitamin A",
        "B": "Vitamin B",
        "C": "Vitamin C",
        "D": "Vitamin D",
        "Correct_Answer": "Vitamin D"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which mineral is necessary for the healthy bones?",
        "A": "Calcium",
        "B": "Iron",
        "C": "Iodine",
        "D": "All of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Calcium"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which mineral is necessary for the formation of blood cell?",
        "A": "Iron",
        "B": "Calcium",
        "C": "Phosphorus",
        "D": "Iodine",
        "Correct_Answer": "Iron"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which diseases is caused due to deficiency of Vitamin D?",
        "A": "Scurvy",
        "B": "Goitre",
        "C": "Night blindness",
        "D": "Rickets",
        "Correct_Answer": "Rickets"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which diseases is caused due to deficiency of Vitamin A?",
        "A": "Scurvy",
        "B": "Night blindness",
        "C": "Rickets",
        "D": "Goitre",
        "Correct_Answer": "Night blindness"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Name the diseases caused due to the deficiency of Iodine?",
        "A": "Scurvy",
        "B": "Obesity",
        "C": "Rickets",
        "D": "Goitre",
        "Correct_Answer": "Goitre"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is caused due to excess of carbohydrates and fats",
        "A": "Scurvy",
        "B": "Goitre",
        "C": "Obesity",
        "D": "None of them",
        "Correct_Answer": "Obesity"
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which of the following is not the function of Water?",
        "A": "Transport digested food in body",
        "B": "Transport harmones in body",
        "C": "Give energy",
        "D": "control body temperature",
        "Correct_Answer": "Give energy"
    }
]